// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What ancient empire is credited with building iconic Taj Mahal?",
    answer: "Mughal Empire",
    options: [
      "Gupta Empire",
      "Mughal Empire",
      "Maurya Empire",
      "Vijayanagara Empire"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which language is considered the primary language of administration in India?",
    answer: "English",
    options: [
      "Hindi",
      "Sanskrit",
      "English",
      "Tamil"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Diwali, the festival of lights, is celebrated to commemorate which event in Hindu mythology?",
    answer: "The victory of Lord Rama over Ravana",
    options: [
      "The birth of Lord Krishna",
      "The victory of Lord Rama over Ravana",
      "The marriage of Lord Shiva and Parvati",
      "The enlightenment of Lord Buddha"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which Indian dish is a savory, deep-fried snack made from chickpea flour?",
    answer: "Pakora",
    options: [
      "Biryani",
      "Samosa",
      "Jalebi",
      "Pakora"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Kathak, a classical dance form of India, originated in which region?",
    answer: "Uttar Pradesh",
    options: [
      "Punjab",
      "Tamil Nadu",
      "Uttar Pradesh",
      "Rajasthan"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which musical instrument is often associated with Indian classical music and is played with a pair of wooden sticks called \"mallets\"?",
    answer: "Tabla",
    options: [
      "Sitar",
      "Tabla",
      "Bansuri",
      "Veena"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The Indus Valley Civilization, one of the world's oldest urban civilizations, flourished in present-day India and which other modern country?",
    answer: "Pakistan",
    options: [
      "Pakistan",
      "Bangladesh",
      "Nepal",
      "Sri Lanka"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 8,
    question: "What architectural marvel in Delhi was commissioned by Mughal emperor Shah Jahan as a residence for his wife Mumtaz Mahal?",
    answer: "Humayun's Tomb",
    options: [
      "Red Fort",
      "Qutub Minar",
      "Lotus Temple",
      "Humayun's Tomb"
    ]
  },
  {
  numb: 9,
  question: "The traditional Indian attire for women, consisting of a long skirt and a blouse, is known as:",
  answer: "Sari",
  options: [
    "Dhoti",
    "Sari",
    "Kurta",
    "Lungi"
  ]
},
{
numb: 10,
question: "Which art form of India involves the painting of intricate designs on the hands and feet, often done during festivals and weddings?",
answer: "Mehndi",
options: [
  "Madhubani",
  "Kalamkari",
  "Rangoli",
  "Mehndi"
]
},


  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];